onnanoko hajimemashita
A tired girl starts her day
tameiki wa bioron no shirabe ni nite
With a sigh like the moan of a violin
akai mi hajikechatta
A cherry bursts in her mouth
mada anata wo shiranai
This was before we had met
konna koto hajimetette
This is the first time I've ever felt like this
manazashi wa aku no hana sakimidarete mo
I could see that your pretty eyes were filled with contempt
ie e to tsuzuku
But I had to go home
basu sutoppu demo anata wa tsurenai
Even at the bus stop, you gave me the cold shoulder
karameta hanabi myaku utsu
The fireworks in the sky pulse
koi no shiruetto
In a silhouette of love
karui mahou
With a little magic,
usotsuki na kuchibiru
Two sets of lying lips
sou kasaneteru
Lock together
ano ne
You see
nee kamisama
God...
warui ko ni naritai yo
I'd like to be a naughty girl
ii ko ni shiteru kara
I'm tired of being good
onegai dayo
So, please
zurui koto sasetoite
It's for a good reason
ii koto shitai nara
So let me be bad for once
sukaato hirogaesu shite
By flipping my skirt
sugu kaeru yo
I'll be back soon
doyoubi wa haresou da
It looks like Saturday is going to be sunny
kamisama hajimemashita
God, it has already started
（講釈師）
女子高生 桃園(ももぞの)奈々生(ななみ)は―
High schooler Momozono Nanami became a god entirely by chance.
ひょんなことから神様になり―
詳しくは 言わぬが花の吉野山
As for the details, the less said about it, the better.
神様を始めてはみたけれど―
She has started trying to be a god, but it has been surprisingly tough!
これが 案外厳しい
Herein begins Chapter 2!
第２話の幕開けでございます
ああ 変な夢見た
Oh, that sure was a weird dream.
My dad had run away, the house had been seized,
お父さんが家出して
家が差し押さえられて―
路頭に迷ってたら 自分の家を
譲ってくれた人がいて―
and I'd become homeless, when a
man gave up his own home for me.
行ってみたら おんぼろ神社で―
But when I went there, it was a rundown shrine, they told me I was a land god
お前は土地神だとか言われて
“えっ？”ってなってたら―
or something, and I was like, "What?"
巴衛(ともえ)とかいう
いけ好かない妖怪が―
And then this obnoxious spirit named Tomoe or whatever
“俺は認めん”とか
勝手なことほざいて―
went blathering on about how this was unacceptable to him and stuff.
その巴衛に 私からキスして
神使になっちゃったって
And then I kissed Tomoe, and he ended up becoming a familiar.
アハハッ どんな夢
What a dream, huh?
（奈々生）
あれ？
Wait...
Um, you did that last time, too.
（講釈師）
あの それ前回もやりましたよ
（奈々生）ここは…
（鬼切(おにきり)）はい 社の本殿
Where am I?
We are in the inner shrine.
（虎徹(こてつ)）
奈々生様のお部屋でございます
It is your room, Lady Nanami.
（奈々生）
でも 昨日と全然様子が違うよ
But it doesn't look anything like the way it did yesterday.
もっと おんぼろだったと
思ったけど
I could've sworn it was a lot more rundown.
In order to make it more livable for you...
（鬼切）
奈々生様が
お暮らしになりやすいようにと
...Master Tomoe readied all of these things.
（虎徹）
巴衛殿が そろえた物でございます
Tomoe did?
（奈々生）
巴衛が？
Why?
どうして？
（鬼切）
昨日 めでたく 巴衛殿を
神使に迎えられたではありませぬか
You successfully made Master Tomoe your familiar yesterday, remember?
It is the duty of the familiar to look after the god.
（虎徹）
神のお世話は
神使の務めでございます
（奈々生）
そうだった！
That's right!
あれは やっぱり 夢じゃなくて
That wasn't a dream after all, and...
私 昨日 巴衛に
無理やりキスなんかして
I forced a kiss on Tomoe yesterday!
Wh-Where's Tomoe?
と… 巴衛は？
Knowing Master Tomoe, he has been...
（鬼切）
巴衛殿なら 先ほどから
...right by your side for some time now.
（虎徹）
奈々生様のすぐおそばに
I forced him to become my familiar.
無理やり 神使に…
Morning, Nanami.
（巴衛）
おはよう 奈々生
お前の寝所が荒れていたので―
Your bedchamber was in a state of neglect,
寝ている間に
しつらえさせてもらったのだ
so I took the liberty of seeing to your accommodations while you slept.
I have prepared all that I could think of.
思いつくかぎりのものは用意した
Though it was against my will,
starting today, I am your familiar.
不本意ではあるが
今日から 俺はお前の神使
I, Tomoe, shall obey your orders without hesitation, regardless of what they may be.
この巴衛
お前の命とあれば―
事のいかんにかかわらず
従うこと やぶさかならず
If you are in need of anything in the future, I humbly ask that you come to me.
これから不便あれば
かしこまって 俺に言うとよい
I'm surprised.
意外
I thought you'd be angrier about being turned into a familiar.
神使にされて
もっと怒ってるかと思ったよ
Did you?
そうか
でも よかった
何か 全然 怒ってないみたいで
But I'm glad you don't seem to be angry at all.
怒るなど生ぬるい
Anger would be tepid.
What?
I am seething with rage!
はらわた 煮えくり返っとるわ！
The humiliation of me having to serve a little girl like you!
この俺が お前のような小娘に
仕えねばならん この屈辱
情けなくて
昨夜は一睡もできなかったわ！
The wretchedness of it kept me from sleeping at all last night!
However, what's done is done.
だが しかたない
As such, I'll have you become a living god worthy of being my lady and mistress.
この上は 俺のあるじにふさわしい
生き神になってもらおう
Worthy?
ふさわしい？
神の力を 通力と呼ぶ
A god's power is called divine power.
Divine Power
The strength of one's divine power increases with use, but...
通力は 使うことによって
力を増すのだが―
Divine Power
For you to increase the level of your divine power,
お前が
通力レベルを上げるためには―
Divine Power
まず 人の祈願を聞き
かなえていくのが手っとり早いな
the quick and easy way would be for you to
hear people's prayers and grant their wishes.
Prayers? Grant them?
祈願？　かなえる？
For example, Mikage is the god of matchmaking.
例えば ミカゲは 縁結びの神
He's granted heaps of matchmaking prayers,
縁結び祈願を
山ほど かなえてきたゆえ―
so his divine powers of matchmaking are extremely strong.
縁を結ぶ通力は
非常に強力だ
Wow. So this is a shrine for matchmaking.
（奈々生）
へえ ここ 縁結びの神社だったんだ
Oh...
He doesn't like me, but he's carefully explaining everything to me.
私のこと 気に入らないのに
丁寧に説明してくれるんだ
（巴衛）
では お前の通力が
どれほどのものか見てみよう
Now, let us see how great your divine powers are.
Try turning this water into sake.
この水を酒に変えてみよ
白札を使ってもかまわん
You may use a white talisman, if you wish.
This thing I used last time, right?
この前使った これね
よし
いいとこ見せてやろうじゃないの
All right! I'll show him how good I am!
はっ！　どうだ！
Sake
How about that?!
Then I shall have a taste.
（虎徹）
では 私めが 味見をば
Th-This is delicious...
こ… これは うまい―
water.
水にございます
Where are you going, Master Tomoe?!
（鬼切）巴衛殿 どこへ？
（巴衛）ほっとけ
Leave me alone!
（鬼切）お待ちくださいませ
（虎徹）我々だけでは 到底非力
Please wait!
We are utterly helpless on our own!
（鬼切）見捨てないでくださいませ
（巴衛）離せ 知らん！
Please do not abandon us!
Let go! To hell with this!
（虎徹）ひきょうです
（巴衛）止めるな！
You cannot do this!
You cannot do this to us, Master Tomoe!
The God Becomes a Target
（テレビ:男性）
おはようございます
ジャポンネット田中(たなか)です
Good morning! Tanaka here at Japon Net!
Lady Nanami, I have brought your meal.
（鬼切）
奈々生様 お食事でございます
Oh...
（テレビ:男性）
いや まだ商品出てませんけど…
（奈々生）
気付けば―
Before I knew it...
寝床も食事も―
my bedroom, my meals...
even the cleaning...
掃除も―
Tomoe had done it all.
全部 巴衛が済ませている
Something about it being the duties of the familiar, he said.
それが 神使の務めだとか
それに比べて私は…
In comparison, I...
The super-popular pop star, Kurama,
（テレビ:レポーター）
超人気アイドルの
ＫＵＲＡＭＡ(クラマ)さんが―
has shockingly, amazingly, incredibly, reportedly transfered here to Ujigami High School!
何と何と何と―
ここ 宇治上(うじがみ)高校に
転入したとのことです
Ujigami High School... That's my school.
宇治上高校 私の学校だ
Now, I'd like to get right with it and do an on-the-spot report!
Who is this Kurama, Lady Nanami?
（鬼切）
ＫＵＲＡＭＡとは
誰でございますか 奈々生様
（虎徹）
超人気アイドルとは 一体…
What in the world is a super-popular pop star?
ＫＵＲＡＭＡが 私の学校に？
Kurama is at my school?!
Please wait, Lady Nanami!
（虎徹）
お待ちください 奈々生様
Where are you going so suddenly?
（鬼切）
急に どこへ行かれます
離して　私 実力テストがあるの
忘れてたのよ
Let go! I-I forgot that I had a proficiency test.
I have to go to school! That's right, school!
行かなきゃ 学校 学校
うん 学校行って友達と遊んで
アイドルにキャーキャー言って―
Yep! Go to school, have fun with my friends, and squeal over pop stars...
Honestly, that's the kind of real world that I belong to!
私の居場所は
やっぱりそんな現実世界なんだわ～
Where do you think you are going?
どこへ行く気だ
They said Kurama is going to my school.
（奈々生）
学校に ＫＵＲＡＭＡが
来るんだって
It's my chance to see Kurama in the flesh.
生ＫＵＲＡＭＡが見られる
チャンスだよ
（巴衛）
何だ そいつは
Who the hell is that?
Kurama is...
（奈々生）
ＫＵＲＡＭＡは…
（講釈師）
ああ 奈々生ちゃん
私が代わりに説明いたしましょう
Oh, darling Nanami, I shall explain in your place.
ＫＵＲＡＭＡとは―
Kurama is the supremely popular super pop star
今 全国の女子高生を
とりこにしている―
超絶人気の
スーパーアイドルでございます
whom high school girls across the
nation are currently enthralled by.
Aside from the premise that he is a fallen angel
with black wings, his bio is shrouded in mystery.
黒い翼を持つ堕天使という設定以外
謎に包まれたプロフィール
That's right! And this guy is at my school!
そう そんな彼が
私の学校にいるんだよ
It's okay if I go, right? Even if I stay here, there aren't going to be any worshipers coming by anyway.
行っていいでしょ
どうせ ここにいたって
参拝者も全然来ないし
Aren't coming by
You may not.
駄目だ
Why not?
何で
（巴衛）
お前を狙う妖怪がいるのは
知っていよう
You must know that there are spirits who are after you.
土地神であるこの印
This mark signifies that you are a land god.
それを お前みたいな小娘が
額に頂いているのだ
And it has been bestowed upon the forehead of a little girl like you.
It's basically asking them to eat you.
やつらに 食ってくれと
言っているようなものだ
Then why don't you come with me, Tomoe?
じゃあ 巴衛も一緒に来れば？
I am busy with shrine work!
俺は 社の仕事で忙しいのだ
And you should learn to wield at least a little divine power!
お前も少しは通力を身につけろ
What a buzz kill.
（奈々生）
けち…
そんなに行きたいなら
行かせてやろう
If you want to go that badly, then I will let you.
What?!
ただし 条件がある
But on one condition.
The Condition
What is that?
（女子生徒１）何あれ
（女子生徒２）嫌だ
Eww!
（奈々生）
くう… 久しぶりの学校なのに
The Condition
And I haven't been back at school in so long, too!
（磯辺(いそべ)）
ハハハッ 何だよ 桃園
What's with you, Momozono?!
（磯辺）
やっと学校に来たと思ったら
その頭
Here I thought you'd finally come to school, and you're wearing that?!
Why am I in the same class with you again, Isobe?
何でまた
あんたと同じクラスなのよ 磯辺
You will wear this hood to hide your forehead.
額を隠すために
この頭巾をかぶるのだ
Tomoe, that jerk!
（奈々生）
巴衛のばか！　悪目立ちじゃん
I'm standing out like a sore thumb!
フフッ 写メっちゃおう
I'm gonna send out a pic!
The...
The fallen angel of darkness!
漆黒の堕天使 ＫＵＲＡＭＡ
Kurama!
（女子生徒たち）
わあ…
（女子生徒１）
あっ 今 ＫＵＲＡＭＡと
目が合った
Kurama and I just locked eyes!
（女子生徒２）
違うし 今の私だし
Nuh-uh! That was with me!
What?
He's coming!
来る
Kurama's coming...
ＫＵＲＡＭＡが
こっちに―
this way!
来る
Hey, hood girl.
（鞍馬）
おい 頭巾女
This is my seat.
ここは 俺の席だ どけ
Move it.
Who's that girl again?
（女子生徒３）
あの子 誰だっけ
You know, the one with the hard-knock life.
（女子生徒４）
ほら あの生活苦の
Oh, I know her.
（女子生徒５）
ああ 知ってる
Momozono...
（女子生徒３）
桃園…
It's Momozono Nanami.
（女子生徒４）
桃園奈々生だよ
Oh! Momozono Nanami.
（女子生徒５）
ああ 桃園奈々生
Ladies' Room
（巴衛）
奈々生
Nanami.
Did you get bullied by some humans or something?
人間に いじめられでもしたか？
な… 何で ここにいるのよ 巴衛
Wh-What are you doing here, Tomoe?!
（巴衛）
心配で見に来たのだ
I was worried, so I came to see you.
Kurama...
（奈々生）
ＫＵＲＡＭＡに
ひどいこと言われた
said something mean to me.
巴衛が こんな頭巾かぶせるから
All because you made me wear this hood!
ＫＵＲＡＭＡという男に
会えたのなら―
If you got your chance to see this guy named Kurama,
もう 学校に用事はなかろう
you must have no more business here at school.
無理するな
Do not strain yourself.
社に帰ろう
Let us return to the shrine.
（奈々生）
私が泣いてるのに―
Here I am, crying...
何で笑ってるのよ
So why are you smiling?
You're not...
巴衛は 私のことなんか
全然 心配してないじゃん
worried about me at all.
巴衛なんか知らない
Forget you, Tomoe!
Were you sobbing in the bathroom?
（鞍馬）
トイレで しくしく泣いてたのか
How cute.
かわいいな
Sorry about earlier, Nanami.
（鞍馬）
さっきは ごめん 奈々生ちゃん
I wasn't crying or anything.
別に泣いてないけど
I apologize. I was irritated.
謝るよ いらついてたんだ
Every day, people at school stare at me, watching me.
毎日 学校の連中に
ジロジロ見物されて―
And I ended up taking it out on you.
それで 君に
八つ当たりしてしまったわけ
だから 安心しなよ
So you can relax.
俺に嫌われたのかもなんて
気に病まなくていいから
You don't have to worry about me hating you or anything.
In that case, I...
（奈々生）
それなら 私―
can't blame you for taking things out on me
あんたに八つ当たりされても
しかたない
because I was staring at you, too.
私も ジロジロ見てた一人だから
そして―
And I won't even be glancing at you anymore, so goodbye!
もう ちらりとも見ないんで
さよなら！
（鞍馬）
おい！
Hey!
So that's what Kurama's really like?
（奈々生）
鞍馬って ああいう人だったの？
こんな頭巾をかぶってまで
会いに来た自分が―
And I went so far as to wear
this hood just to come see him?
いよいよ ばかみたいだ
I'm really starting to feel like an idiot.
Poor Lady Nanami!
（鬼切）
奈々生様 おかわいそうに
（虎徹）
巴衛殿にいじめられて
Bullied by Master Tomoe!
（鬼切）
あのように
悲嘆に暮れてしまわれた
And now, look how overcome with grief she is!
Hold it. I did not bully her.
待て 俺は いじめてない
But...
だが…
I suppose the one who made her cry...
泣かせたのは 俺か
was me.
Momozono of the hard-knock life!
生活苦の桃園よう
What kind of poor man's lunch did you bring today?!
今日は
どんな貧乏弁当持ってきたのよ
余計なお世話よ 弁当なんて…
It's none of your business! My lunch is...
Lunch...
Oh? Don't tell me you forgot it.
（磯辺）
あっ まさかお前
忘れたんじゃないだろうな　ウケる
That's hilarious!
I-I'm buying bread today!
きょ… 今日は パンなの！
You've got money to buy bread?
お前が
パン買う金なんか あんのかよ
あるわよ 失礼ね
Of course, I do! How insulting!
D-Do I? Have money? Oh, here.
（奈々生）
あ… あったっけな お金なんて
あっ これ…
ほら
See?
No way! Why do you have a whole 30,000?!
うそだろ！
何でお前が３万も持ってんの
（奈々生）
あれ？　これ私の？
What? Is this mine?
There's no way I had this much on me.
こんなに持ってるはずない
What the? I'm missing three big ones.
あれ？　諭吉が３枚 足りないな
Well, I guess 30,000 is no big deal.
まあ 別にいいか ３万くらい
Hey, does anyone know what
happened to Kurama's money?
（北見(きたみ)）
ちょっと 誰か
鞍馬様のお金 知らない？
（女子生徒１）
桃園さん そのお金 どうしたの
Momozono, where did you get that money?
What?
That's exactly 30,000 yen, too.
（女子生徒２）
ちょうど３万円だし
Weird, isn't it?
（北見）
変よね
（女子生徒２）
鞍馬様の財布から抜いたんじゃ…
Maybe she swiped it from Kurama's wallet.
I didn't!
（奈々生）
違うよ
After all, Momozono's family is...
（女子生徒２）
だって 桃園さんの家って…
（鞍馬）
ちょっと待って
Hold on a second.
I just remembered.
思い出した
I gave her that 30,000.
その３万は
俺が彼女にあげたんだよ
Because she said she didn't have money to buy bread.
パン買う金がないって
言ってたからさ
What's that supposed to mean?
（奈々生）
何それ
Right, Nanami?
だよな 奈々生ちゃん
That's not true!
（奈々生）
違う
That's not true!
I apologize that it took so long to make the arrangements, Lady Nanami.
奈々生様 支度が遅くなり
申し訳ありません
今日は 奈々生様の
めでたい初登校日
Today is your joyous first day at school.
この巴衛が 腕を振るった
昼げの膳―
I, Tomoe, used every ounce of skill to prepare this midday meal.
Please enjoy it.
どうぞお召し上がりください
And if I might have everyone's attention.
そして 皆々様に申し上げる
Lady Nanami is our cherished lady and mistress.
奈々生様は 我らの大切なあるじ
無礼な物言いや 振る舞い等
一切 この巴衛が許しませぬ
If any of you speak to her or treat her with disrespect,
you will answer to me.
Master Kurama.
鞍馬殿
The three bills that you purportedly lost...
なくしたという 札３枚
They appear to be on the floor by your feet, but what say you?
足元に落ちているように見えるが
いかがか
What?
No way! I put that 30,000 in Nanami's pocket.
（鞍馬）
うそだろ
この３万 俺が 奈々生の
ポケットに入れておいたのに
To all of you, her classmates,
ご学友の皆様
I humbly ask that you look after our Lady Nanami.
何とぞ 奈々生様のこと
よろしくお願いいたします
Tomoe...
（奈々生）
巴衛…
The only person who cares about me...
私のこと 思ってくれるのは…
Hurry up and eat.
さっさと食え
In all the world,
（奈々生）
世界で たった一人
Tomoe might be the only one.
この巴衛だけかもしれない
right up
Next part coming
Next
part
starting
Next
part
starting
Next
part
starting
Next
part
starting
Next
part
starting
（講釈師）
いやはや何だか
怒とうのスタートを切った―
Goodness gracious, darling Nanami's school days
seem to have gotten off to a rather turbulent start.
奈々生ちゃんのスクールデイズ
How will her second day go?
その２日目や いかに
See you later!
（奈々生）
いってきま～す
（巴衛）
奈々生 忘れ物だぞ
Nanami, you are forgetting some things.
This three-layer lunch box that I, Tomoe, poured my heart and soul into making
この巴衛が腕によりをかけた
３段重ね弁当と―
and the cat hood decorated with a
seasonal flower made by yours truly.
巴衛作 季節の花を添えて作った
猫頭巾だ
Sorry, I'll say no to the hood today. I'll be fine without it.
ごめん　今日は頭巾はいいや
なくても平気 学校行くだけだし
I'm only going to school, after all.
（巴衛）
何を言う
What are you saying?
Walking around alone without even wearing a
hood is as good as heading off to battle naked.
頭巾もかぶらず一人歩きするなど
裸で戦場に赴くも同然
You can say that once you are
capable of defending yourself.
そんなせりふは 自分の身が
守れるようになってから言え
To begin with, I believe school is...
（巴衛）大体 俺は学校など…
（奈々生）お弁当多いから―
That's a lot of lunch, so one layer's enough.
１段だけでいいや
いってきま～す
See you later!
（鬼切）ああ 巴衛殿
（虎徹）しっかり
Oh, Master Tomoe!
Please hang in there!
いや うっとうしい頭巾がないと
こんなにすっきり
Whew! It feels so good not to be wearing that annoying hood!
（女子生徒１）桃園さ～ん！
（奈々生）うん？
Momozono!
Morning!
（女子生徒２）
おはよう
Oh, girls from my class!
（奈々生）
あっ クラスの子　もう友達が…
Am I already making friends?
Morning!
おはよう
Hey, is Tomoe coming again today?
（女子生徒３）
ねえねえ 今日も巴衛君来る？
（女子生徒１）
来たら うちらのこと
紹介してほしいんだけど
If he comes, we want you to introduce us to him.
Uh, I brought my lunch with me today,
ええと 今日は 私
お弁当持ってきたから―
so I don't think he'll be coming.
来ないと思うよ
（女子生徒たち）
何だ つまんない
Aw, that's no fun.
Girls!
（奈々生）
女子…
（クラクション）
（奈々生）うん？
No hood today, Nanami?
今日は 頭巾なしか
奈々生ちゃん
Get in. I'll give you a ride.
乗れよ 送ってやる
Kurama...
（奈々生）
鞍馬…
No thanks!
いらない
Why not? Are you being shy?
何で？　シャイなのかな
それとも 俺の人気に…
Or are you intimidated by my popularity?
あんたが嫌いだからだっつうの
It's because I hate you. That's why.
Who does she think she is?!
（女子生徒４）
何 あの女
（女子生徒５）
何触ってんの？　離れなさいよ
意味分かんないんだけど！
How dare she touch him?!
Get real!
Pop stars are a pain.
（奈々生）
アイドル めんどくさ…
That Nanami...
（巴衛）
奈々生のやつめ
言われたとおり
頭巾をかぶればいいのに
All she had to do was wear the hood like I said.
But now, I must watch over her all day long.
おかげで俺は
一日中見張らねばならん
And I have not even made preparations for dinner yet.
夕飯の仕込みもまだなのに
Sweetfish grilled with a sprinkle of salt might be nice for tonight.
（虎徹）
こよいは
アユの塩焼きなど良いですな
Preparing meals and guarding a girl.
（巴衛）
飯の支度に 娘の守り
Are these the duties of a familiar?
これが 神使の仕事か
How boring.
退屈だな
At times, I feel a fierce longing...
時々 無性に懐かしくなる
for my old life of spine-tingling thrills.
昔の 血湧き肉躍る生活
Master Tomoe.
（虎徹）
巴衛殿
Master Tomoe, Lady Nanami
appears to be going somewhere.
巴衛殿
奈々生様が
どこかへ行かれるようです
I'll be
waiting
on the
roof.
-Kurama
Why'd you drag me all the way out here?
What do you want, Kurama?
こんなとこに呼び出して何の用
I'll be
waiting
on the
roof.
-Kurama
I'll be
waiting
on the
roof.
-Kurama
I'll be
waiting
on the
roof.
-Kurama
鞍馬
First of all, I want to ask you something.
まず先に聞いておきたい
All I have to do is meet their gaze and every girl blushes and looks down,
どの女も 俺が目を合わせてやれば
頬を赤らめ 視線を落とすのに―
but for some reason, you alone claim to hate me.
どうしてか お前だけは
俺を嫌いと言う
Why is that?
なぜだ
（奈々生）
こいつ…
This guy...
I spoke up for you when you
were being accused yesterday.
昨日は 責められてるお前を
かばってやったし―
謝ってもやった
And I even apologized.
何が気に入らないのか
全く分からないんだけど
I have no idea what you're so unhappy about.
He's clueless!
（奈々生）
天然だ
If you wanted, I wouldn't be against becoming yours...
お前が望むなら―
俺は お前のものに
なってやらなくも…
ばっかじゃないの
Are you stupid or what?
Yes, stup...
そう ばか…
Stupid?!
ばかだと！
If you keep acting high and mighty and looking down on everyone,
そんな上から目線で
ふんぞり返ってたら―
you'll never find a girlfriend, much less make any friends.
彼女どころか 友達もできないよ
If there's nothing else, I'm leaving.
他に用がないなら帰るよ
じゃあね
Later.
What I want isn't anything of the sort.
（鞍馬）
俺が欲しいものは
そんなものじゃない
Land god...
土地神 お前を
手に入れることができれば―
If I can make you mine, I...
俺は…
What's this?
何だ
背中に寒気
A chill down my spine...
Found you, you damn spirit.
見つけたぞ 妖怪め
You're...
お前は…
You have sharp eyes to have set
your sights on Nanami so quickly.
早速 奈々生に目をつけるとは
目ざといやつ
The familiar from yesterday!
昨日の神使か！
Kurama...
（巴衛）
鞍馬…
そうか お前
I see. You must be...
A crow spirit of Mount Kurama.
鞍馬山(くらまやま)の烏天狗(からすてんぐ)
It has been sixteen years since my descent.
下山して16年
Now that you have seen my true identity,
正体を見られたからには―
you must die!
死んでもらう！
A blade of air?!
（巴衛）
かまいたちか
どうだ きつね　お前の妖術は
なかなか便利なようだ
How about this, fox? Your spirit powers seem quite handy.
俺が 土地神になった暁には―
When I have become the land god, I would not be against bringing you on as my familiar.
お前を神使に
迎え入れてやってもよいぞ
You would prefer me over that girl, too, wouldn't you?
お前だって あの娘より
俺のほうがいいだろう
You can become a land god?
（巴衛）
お前が土地神になれるのか
Sure, I can.
（鞍馬）
なれるとも
I just have to take one bite of the girl's heart, right?
娘の心臓を
一かじりすればいいんだろう
What fun this is, crow.
楽しいな 天狗
What?!
When I think of how bastards like you will be coming for Nanami,
お前みたいなやつが
奈々生目当てに来るかと思うと―
I could not be happier that she is the land god.
奈々生が土地神で 万々歳だ
What?
何…
Os!
Ostrich meat is low in calories and full of iron and other minerals.
ダチョウの肉は低カロリーで
鉄分 ミネラルが豊富なのだ
How lucky for you, Kurama.
よかったな 鞍馬
土地神になりたいのだっけ？
You want to become a land god, was it?
（鞍馬）
チョッ？
Trich!
If I feed you to Nanami, you will be able to become part of her flesh.
お前を奈々生に食わせれば
奈々生の血肉の一部となれるぞ
I will bring all my skills to bear to make you a land god.
俺が 腕によりをかけて
お前を土地神にしてやろう
ガ～！　チョ～ン！
Os!
Trich!
What fun this is. Today, we will have a whole roasted ostrich.
楽しいな 今日は鳥の丸焼きだ
Whoa! What the?! An ostrich?!
（男子生徒）
何だ ダチョウって 聞いてないよ！
That's news to me!
（鞍馬）
神使？
あいつのどこが神使だよ
A familiar?! How is any part of what he does the work of a familiar?!
Someone! Stop that fox for me!
誰か あのきつねを止めてくれ！
Land god!
土地神！
"I can't hold back these feelings anymore!"
（奈々生）
もう止められない この気持ちは
Oh, congratulations, Lisa!
Beverly Hills
High School Diaries
ああ リサ おめでとう
マイクと幸せに
I wish you happiness with Mike!
私も こんな高校生活を
送ってみたい
I wish my high school life was like this, too.
（男子生徒１）
何か ダチョウが
火の玉に追いかけられてるってよ
I heard that an ostrich is being chased by a ball of fire or something!
（男子生徒２）
何だそれ
What the hell?
（鞍馬）
ダチョ ダチョ ダチョ…
Ostrich! Ostrich! Ostrich! Ostrich! Ostrich! Ostrich!
What?!
I knew it! Tomoe's foxfire!
やっぱり 巴衛のきつね火
There's someone there!
（奈々生）
人が！
Watch out!
危な～い！
A-Are you okay?
だ… 大丈夫？
（あみ）
ふにゃあ…
チョ～…
Trich...
That pendant...
このペンダント
Tomoe!
巴衛！
Nurse's Office
（奈々生）
けががなかったから
よかったようなものの―
No one was hurt, so maybe it turned out all right,
but you've got some nerve
going on a rampage at school!
学校で暴れるなんて
どういう神経よ
I thought to protect you.
お前を守ろうと思ったのだ
So? Why is Kurama a bird?
で… 何で鞍馬が 鳥になってんのよ
That guy is not human.
その男は人間ではない
He's a crow spirit.
烏天狗という妖怪だ
Huh?!
地獄の堕天使じゃなかったの？
I thought you were supposed to be a fallen angel from Hell!
A-Anyway, turn Kurama back to the way he was.
とりあえず 鞍馬を元に戻すのよ
But tonight's dinner...
でも 今日の夕飯が…
Turn him back!
戻しなさい
Listen to me, Kurama.
いい？　鞍馬
今回は助けてあげるから―
I'll help you this time,
so no making trouble at school or making mischief around me.
学校で問題起こしたり―
私に悪さしないの
Promise, okay?
約束だよ
死ぬかと思った
I thought I was a goner...
Wait, Kurama.
鞍馬 ちょっと
What do you want?! You got some
problem with me being a crow spirit?!
何だよ 天狗で何か文句あるのかよ
顔…
Your face.
（奈々生）
けがしてるよ
You're hurt.
とりあえず 消毒しとこう
Let's get it disinfected for now.
Leave it.
（鞍馬）
ほっとけ
何言ってんの
What are you saying?
アイドルが
顔に傷つけちゃ駄目でしょ
Pop stars can't get scars on their faces.
I don't like you,
私は あんたのこと
好きじゃないけど―
but there are tons of girls out there who do.
外には あんたを好きな子が
山盛りいるんだから
You have to at least do a proper job of maintaining your looks,
外見だけは ちゃんと保たなきゃ
or you'd be doing a disservice to those girls.
その子たちに悪いでしょ
ah ah ah ah
Right...
Hold it.
（巴衛）
待て
In the end, I am the one who gets yelled at, and this guy gets his injuries treated?!
最終的に俺が怒られて―
ah ah ah ah
この男が傷の手当てを
されているというのは―
ah ah ah ah
どういうことだ！
How does that work?!
（奈々生）
だって 巴衛は
けがしてないじゃん
But you're not hurt, Tomoe.
（巴衛）
俺が無傷なのは
俺のおかげであって…
I owe my lack of injuries to my own skills.
ah ah ah ah
Or rather, what are you doing at school, Tomoe?
（奈々生）
っていうかさ 何で巴衛が
学校にいるのよ
ah ah ah ah
Nanami...
That is your fault!
（ミカゲ）
奈々生さん
いい神様 始めましたね
You've started being a good god.
It's not like I asked you to come.
ah ah ah ah
Now you listen to me well, Nanami!
（巴衛）奈々生 よく聞け
（奈々生）何よ
What?!
（巴衛）
あしたからは
絶対に頭巾をつけて登校しろ
Starting tomorrow, you are absolutely wearing a hood to school!
ah ah ah ah
Absolutely not!
（奈々生）
絶対 嫌…
kamisama onegai da
Please, God
boku no
I...
ano hito ni aitai no sa
I want to meet her
ah ah ah
ah ah ah ah
kamisama tsurain da
God, I'm in pain
kyou mo mata nou ni
Because, she...
konakatta
didn't come today either.
onegai ga aru no kamisama
I have a request, God
boku wo tasukete
Please, save me
ah ah ah ah
kamisama mou osoi
God, it's too late for me
ano ko wa...
Because she's...
Preview
（講釈師）
土地神になった奈々生の元に―
Now that Nanami has become the land god,
Himemiko of the Swamp comes to pay her a visit.
Touku sora ni
gone off into the distant sky
沼皇女(ぬまのひめみこ)が訪ねてきた
ななな… 何と
人間の男を好きになったという
Sh-Sh-Sh-Shockingly, she claims to
have fallen in love with a human boy.
Kieta no sa
and disappeared
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Love between a spirit and a human... Can that work?
あやかしと人間の恋
それってあり？
Sayonara baby
Farewell, baby
次回「神様、縁をむすぶ」
Next time, "The God Makes a Match."
The God Makes a Match
Love is real.
ラブ イズ リアル…
Goodbye